A sure thing comes once in a lifetime... but the real thing lasts forever.
The Sure Thing is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Rob Reiner.
Gib, a beer-guzzling slob, and Alison, an uptight Ivy-Leaguer, are an unlikely
duo stuck together on a cross-country trip during Christmas break.
At first they get on each other's nerves but, as time passes, they
find their divergent natures complement each other.
Now they need to realize what they've already found before it's too late.
Walter "Gib" Gibson, played by John Cusack.
Alison Bradbury, played by Daphne Zuniga.
Lance, played by Anthony Edwards.
Jason, played by Boyd Gaines.
Gary Cooper, played by Tim Robbins.
Mary Ann Webster, played by Lisa Jane Persky.
The Sure Thing is a 1985 American romantic comedy road film directed by Rob Reiner and
starring John Cusack, Daphne Zuniga, Viveca Lindfors, and Nicollette Sheridan.
The film chronicles the cross-country journey of college students Walter Gibson (Cusack) and Alison Bradbury (Zuniga) as they make
their way from New England to Los Angeles over Christmas break, each in an effort to meet their ideal romantic match.
Written by Steven L.
Bloom and Jonathan Roberts, The Sure Thing marked Reiner's second directorial feature
after This Is Spinal Tap (1984), and Cusack's first major starring role.
Released theatrically in the spring of 1985, The Sure Thing was a box-office success and received mostly favorable reviews from film critics, who commended it for its traditional comedic structure,
with some likening it to a modern version of Frank Capra's It Happened One Night (1934),  though Reiner himself stated that the parallels between the two films were unintentional.
In 2017, the British Film Institute ranked The Sure Thing
among Reiner's top five feature films.
The film explores themes of california, college, road
trip, swimming pool, cross country.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.